HANIYEH FATHOLAHI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Email: haniyeh.fath@gmail.com

Location: Dortmund, North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/h-fatholahi



SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with 5 years of work experience in medium-sized and large companies providing software solutions in the fields of intelligent transportation, fleet tracking, payment and insurance systems. Having worked in these companies, I am skilled in system analysis, design and backend development.

My expertise is now to design and develop applications and systems using Java and NodeJS including their related frameworks, technologies and tools such as different databases - SQL and NoSQL databases. In addition, experienced in developing IoT based services using IoT brokers or WebSocket like management and communication services. It is worth mentioning that I am interested in microservice architecture and cloud software development.

SKILLS

Languages Java, NodeJS, TypeScript

Technologies Spring framework, Spring boot, Hibernate, JPA, Express JS

Tools Maven, Docker, Git, CI/CD

Software engineering OOP, System design, DDD, Scrum, Agile

Architecture SOA, Microservice, MVC

Databases Oracle, MongoDB, Redis, Cassandra

Web technologies RESTful, SOAP, HTML, CSS

Soft skills Teamwork, Self-study, Problem-solving mindset, Debugging, Adaptability

EXPERIENCES

MAY 2021 - MAR 2022

JAVA DEVELOPER IN INSURANCE CORE INSURANCE, DOTIN, TEHRAN

My roles in the company:

- Contributed to design and develop the system new service, legal insurance
- Refactored 100% of the code for annual insurance branch performance report in order to increase reusability
- Refactored financial features in order to improve performance and reusability
- Designed and implemented marketers reporting dashboard
- Improved WebSocket notification service memory consumption by tunning the configuration of the message broker and refactoring the existing code

OCT 2016 - FEB 2021

R&D DEPARTMENT SOFTWARE ENGINEER, MAGFA, TEHRAN

My roles in the company:

- Developed fleet tracking services for GPS tracking systems containing about 3000 online tracker devices
- Optimized performance by using multithreading and queuing
- Designed and implemented Rest APIs for fleet tracking applications and services
- Collaborated with Frontend team in order to upgrade frontend technologies
- Designed and developed a USSD Wrapper service for USSD based mobile payments

SEP 2016 - MAR 2020

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, TOOBATECH, TEHRAN

My roles in the company:

- Technical lead of Toobatel Instant messaging system project for Alzahra university
- Designed and implemented 100% chatting system in Toobatel app using MQTT brokers
- Designed and implemented Toobatel bot engine in order to integrate student services
- Designed and implemented Web applications based on customers' requirement

EDUCATION

2012 - 2016

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, ALZAHRA UNIVERSITY, TEHRAN

Dissertation Title: "implementing IoT platform by customizing Openstack cloud computing Infrastructure APIs for collecting metrics from IoT nodes."

LANGUAGES

• Persian: Native

English: Fluent (TOEFL iBT certificate – C2)
German: Basic (taking in A2 level classes)